JORGEN BAERTSCH

🗣 SEATTLE, WA, US 🔤 jpbaertsch@gmail.com 🔲 +1(218) 348-8032 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jorgen-baertsch-8673b2142/

https://jpbaer.github.io/React-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

As a highly skilled full-stack software engineer with 3 years of experience in aerospace systems, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and problem-solving skills to any project. With proficiency in multiple programming languages, including Python and JavaScript frameworks such as Node.Js, MongoDB and React, I am equipped to deliver cutting-edge solutions that exceed expectations.

EXPERIENCE

Recording/Mixing Engineer

Lost Boys Studios

August 2021 - Present, US, WA, Seattle

· Utilize a wide variety of hardware and software devices to record, edit, and mix audio to provide client's with a professional song that meets and exceeds industry expectations.

Aerospace Systems Engineer

Left Hand Design

June 2018 - March 2021, US, CO, Longmont

- · Aided in the development, procurement, and sale of Fast-Steering Mirrors for use in laser communication and defense systems.
- Interfaced with customers to answer requests for information, develop system requirements, price tables and proposals leading in the generation of multiple contracts ranging from \$500,000 to \$5 million dollars.
- $\cdot \ \text{Maintained assembly travelers and performed tests to ensure critical design requirements were being met.}$

PROJECTS

Project Manager/Backend Lead - Music Sharing Social Media App

March 2023 - March 2023

- · Successfully built application using Node. Is and SQL that integrates Spotify API our own REST API and database to pull and display users listening habits and playlists in social media like feed.
- · Developed feature for authentication, unique user profiles, messaging between users, and like and comment functionality.
- \cdot Managed team of 4 using agile methodology for timelines and task delegation.

Ecommerce Back-end

March 2023 - March 2023

- Built a functional REST API for an e-commerce backend utilizing Node.Js, Express, and MySQL that allows user to get, create, update, and delete data for products, product categories, and associated tags.
- · Utilized insomnia to test functionality of API routes.

Project Manager/Backend Lead - Real Estate App

February 2023 - February 2023

- · Developed a website using Javascript's Node. Js that utilizes an external real estate API to search cities and display current houses for sale.
- · Lead the integration of geo-location data from Google Maps API to fetch data from the real estate API at users location.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science In Aerospace Engineering

University of Colorado at Boulder · US, Colorado, Boulder · 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Development Certification

EdEx Bootcamps via University of Washington · 20232

Primary Skills Gained: React, NodeJs, SQL, MongoDB, Express, Javascript, HTML, CSS

SKILLS

JavaScript, Node.JS, SQL, MongoDB, React, HTML, CSS, Python, Git, REST API Development, GraphQL, Data Structures, Algorithms, System Design, Project Management, Docker, Jest, MVC, Microsoft Office